

University of Minnesota, Department of Political Science

□701.610.8586 | ➡logan.stundal@gmail.com | ☆loganstundal.com | ⊡loganstundal | ⊡logan-stundal | ♥loganstundal

Summary_

PhD candidate with 5+ years experience presenting research to diverse audiences and summarizing findings in written formats, project management and budgeting experience, and familiarity with a variety of research methods. Eager to put my data analysis, research, and management skills to use in US Federal government work advancing program, agency, and US strategic interests. Published work on event-data validation, well-received teaching reviews (Average Score: 5.7/6.0), and multiple collaborative team-based research projects.

• Expected PhD completion: May/June 2022

Education

University of Minnesota Minneapolis, MN

PHD, Political Science Expected: May/June 2022

University of MinnesotaMinneapolis, MNMA, Political Science2021

University of North Dakota Grand Forks, ND

BA, Political Science & Economics (Magna Cum Laude)

Skills_

GENERAL

 Public speaking, written communication (memo and reports), project management and planning, program budgeting, grant application, data analysis, data cleaning and organization, collaborative reasearch and team-based project work

PROGRAMMING

- Expert: R (especially Tidyverse, ggplot, and sf spatial libraries), GIS, MS Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
- Proficient: Python, SQL, Stan, LaTex, Git, Javascript, Google Earth Engine environment

DATA ANALYSIS

• Dynamic modeling (spatial and time series), geostatistical analysis, panel data methods, Bayesian analysis, data visualization and mapping, data cleaning, surveys

RESEARCH

- Substantive: Armed conflict, conflict event-data validation, health in conflict zones, international affairs, US foreign policy
- Research Methods: Research design, diffusion and contagion processes, simulation techniques

Experience

University of Minnesota

PHD CANDIDATE 2016 - Present

- Dissertation explores the causal connections between armed conflict and disease using mixed-methods including interviews (planned spring 2022) and large-n subnational spatiotemporal analysis
- · Presented research to non-technical audiences at various colloquia and national / international conferences
- · Completed Institutional Review Board (IRB) protocol and trainings required for research with victimized populations
- Submitted grant applications with project-specific budgets to support ongoing research
- Extensively documented research and coding decisions through Git and Github

RESEARCH ASSISTANT 2017 - Present

- Served in multiple research assitant roles: coding international legal standards, cleaning and analyzing international survey data, and collecting evidence of Chinese military activity in the domain of public health
- · Maintained reproducible workflows setting up research working directories to secure data and results
- · Prepared and presented summary reports of research efforts in weekly or bi-weekly status update meetings

TEACHING ASSISTANT 2017-2021

- · Organized and graded student assignments while observing strict confidentiality requirements
- · Managed and maintained student-facing class websites posting updates and required documents
- Provided detailed feedback to students on written work (example: policy memos)
- Scheduled student meetings and resolved disputes

PROJECT MANAGER - METHODS CONFERENCE ORGANIZER

2018-2020

- Planned large conferences of 30+ nationally representative graduate students for 2 consecutive years
- · Drafted budget request and grant application documents outlining program goals and itemized funding needs
- · Secured funding of approximately \$10,000 from various college units and grant-funding organizations to cover conference expenses
- Prepared and presented itemized budgetary expense reports to grant-funding agencies
- · Managed logistics for conference presenter lodging and food for all (approximately 100) conference attendees

INSTRUCTOR OF RECORD 2018, 2019

- Provided instruction in US Foreign Policy and Undergraduate Research Methods
- US Foreign Policy: Lectured on topics including US counterterrorism policy, novel strategic challenges, and current (circa Fall 2018) US foreign
 policy posturing
- Research Methods: Trained students in descriptive data analysis through multiple linear regression, fielded *Qualtrics* surveys with student-written questions, and instructed students in *R* programming language
- · Managed classrooms with 70-150 students
- · Maintained confidential student records

University of Michigan

GRADUATE TEACHING INSTRUCTOR - ADVANCED EMPIRICAL MODELING (ICPSR GRADUATE SEMINAR)

2020 202

- Taught R code and advanced statistical modeling to graduate students and new professors
- · Optimized lectures for asynchronous attendance from participants globally
- · Offered research consultation in office hours

Other

PRIVATE CONSULTING 2019

- Provided multi-week (3-hour) training sessions to local businesses on uses and applications of the R programming language
- Soliticited feedback from business contacts to better understand their specific needs prior to trainings
- Wrote and presented code-examples demonstrating how attendees could integrate reproducable analysis into existing organizational workflows

Select Awards, Grants, & Fellowships.

- 2019 University of Minnesota Thank a Teacher Award
- 2018 National Science Foundation (NSF), Graduate Research Fellowhip Program Honorable Mention
- Empirical Implications of Theoretical Models Certification / Fellowship, Inter-university Consortium for
- 2017 Political and Social Research (ICPSR) (NSF Funded)
- 2016 Larson Graduate Research Fellowship in Political Economy
- 2009 Ronald E. McNair Post-Baccalaureate Fellowship

Publications, Select Working Papers, and Public Writing

- Stundal, L. (2022). Working title: Epidemiology and war: Disease, conflict, and public health [PhD thesis].
 University of Minnesota.
- 2. Stundal, L., Bagozzi, B., Freeman, J., & Holmes, J. (n.d.). Human rights violations in space: Assessing the external validity of machine geo-coded vs. Human geo-coded data. *Political Analysis*.
- 3. Fazal, T., & Stundal, L. (2021). Mapping US and chinese health diplomacy.
- 4. Stundal, L., Bagozzi, B., & Freeman, J. (2021). *Geostatistical analysis in space and time: An examination of insurgent activity during the iraq war.*
- Fazal, T., & Stundal, L. (2019). "Measles, ukraine, and civil war: The missing links". Political Violence at a Glance. https://politicalviolenceataglance.org/2019/07/22/measles-ukraine-and-civil-war-the-missing-links/